[Music]
hello everyone I'm Sarco a product
manager for business Central in this
presentation I will show you what's new
in power pages on business Central
virtual
tables so if you remember uh Power pages
on Virtual tables has been in public
review since since last uh 23rd Wave 2
uh release right so now in a 24 wave 1
release we are introducing a small
feature that has been in high demand by
many um partners and customer which is
multi compan support through data verse
shared execution variable so later in
the demo I will show The Following I
will first review the access to Business
Center data enabled by power pages on
Virtual tables Anonymous or
authenticated access for external user
as well as authenticated access for
internal users and then I'll show you
the standard global company setting used
by virtual table plug-in for all users
and apps uh and power Pages portals and
then I will show you also the standard
user specific company setting used by
virtual table plug-in to overwrite the
global one so in this case for each user
you can have a targeting one company and
then all apps and uh Power Pages portal
will will use that company to show the
data from uh business Central so the new
feature is essentially allowing uh
virtual table plugin to use a data vers
shared execution variable that we call
BC Company ID with this uh shared
execution variable a virtual table
plug-in can actually overwrite both the
global and user specific company setting
so in this case you can have multiple
power Pages uh portals addressing
different um uh company in business
Central so this is the the feature that
um uh was not supported before multic
company support and finally I will show
you how to build custom data verse
mapping plugin and mapping table that
can be created to set the BC Company ID
shared variable for any combination of
users power apps and power Pages portals
all right so before I uh before I go to
the demo let me uh give you a review of
anonymous or authenticated access for
external internal users that enabled
with power pages on Virtual tables there
are three scenarios that's enabled by
this uh this feature first is anonymous
read only access for external or
unlicensed user without signing in so uh
uh Power Pages allow you to create for
example a B2B portal so customer does
not have to sign into the portal and
when they visit it they can see business
Central data uh even though they are
unlicensed right the second um type of
access is authenticated authenticated
access for external or unlicensed user
after registration and signing in and
finally uh the third type of access is
authenticated access for internal or
license user after they sign in so the
third type of access is essentially the
same like a business Central uh virtual
tables so you actually have to be
licensed to be able to access a business
Central virtual tables in data verse the
first two you don't need to be licensed
so uh you might ask the question uh
what's the difference betweenin external
on internal user so I'll show you an
excerpt from the Dynamics 365 licensing
guide it essentially says that external
user are those user who have a employee
who are not in an employee like
relationship so they are actually uh
they're not in an employee like
relationship most of most of the time
they are user from the customer or
vendor organizations who who need to
access um uh business Central data but
they don't have a license for example in
the process of um customer onboarding or
vendor um uh vendor biding process so
this type of user can be allowed to
access business Central data through
Power pages okay and internal users are
essentially uh those user or um uh those
user who actually employee or those user
who actually
performing uh business processes on the
behalf of the company with business with
business Central license so this
internal user have to have a license to
access business Central data from
anywhere all right so that's a little
bit of um illustration and diagram the
differentiating between external and
internal user and now let me show you
how actually the custom data verse
mapping plugin and table will work to
allow multi company
support in the standard um um uh Power
Pages portal access to business centeral
virtual tables it will use um um a data
verse cruit API that will be translated
by the table plugin into business
Central cruit API targeting the business
Central company that's configured uh in
the global or user specific company
settings this is standard that's been
around for a while right but now you can
actually create a custom data versus
mapping plugin T plugin and table where
the plug plugin can be created to
intercept any power apps or any power
Pages portal trying to access a selected
business Central virtual tables through
the data ver grou API for example you
can actually create a mapping
plugin where whenever uh Power Pages
portal try to access the sales invoice
virtual table for business Central
through the re retrieve or retrieve
multiple which is the re API for the
this plugin can be actually triggered
and this plugin will actually work with
the mapping table to find any
combination of user and a portal that is
assigned to their specific business
Central comp company so in this example
if Portal 2 has a mapping table record
that targets company to the mapping
plugin will set the shared BC Company ID
variable to company to so then uh next
when the uh virtual table plug-in
actually pick up the operation it will
then use the content of the BC Company
ID uh variable the shared variable to
translate data ver cruit API into
business Central cruit API targeting
company to and completely overriding the
global and user specific company
settings and how do we actually create
and register this plugin and uh create
the content for the mapping table so
it's very simple and you can actually
look at the the link in this
presentation which is a um learn uh
learning document from uh dataverse um
uh sites there's a dataverse plug-in
documentation and how to register right
so um you will see in the screenshot
there's a a plug-in registration tool
where in this case I'm actually
registering my um company mapping plugin
to intercept retrieve and retrieve
multiple access to sales invoice virtual
table so whenever there's a site that
trying to read a sales invoice table
which is virtualized in data verse this
plugin will be triggered when the uh the
plug-in will triggered is very important
because you want to actually make sure
that you prepare the shared variable
before the um before the virtual table
plug-in can use it right so in this case
um in the next picture you can see that
uh I set it up to intercept at the
prevalidation stage so now we have the
uh mapping plug-in you can actually
create a Content or a record in the
mapping table to make sure that a
certain site will be uh targeting
a certain business Central company so
for example um if you have a portal and
in the URL of this uh power power Pages
portal you put _ Services slab you can
actually see the portal ID which is
actually a good right and you can
actually enter this good into your uh
mapping table what I call in here uh app
name company mappings right and you can
see here uh the last the the last row
for portal ID um the one that I show in
the screen screen uh 1 e c 2 e Etc right
it's actually mapping or targeting my
company so whenever that portal is open
it will always use my company as The Bu
business Central um uh company to Target
and it will override the global and user
specific
settings the code for the plugin looks
very simple so this is a very um a short
cat um um that will be published in the
in our documentation after the business
Central launch it will deal with two
trigger so basically whenever you launch
a power apps targeting um uh Business
Center virtual table or whenever you
launch a power page portal targeting the
business center virtual table in the
case of power Pages it will actually uh
parse the user agent of the power pages
and try to pick the portal ID from that
user agent of the power Pages portal
once it get the uh the portal ID it will
look at the mapping table if there's a
record with that portal ald if there is
a record with that portal ald it will
take the value of the company ID and put
that value into um uh BC Company ID
shared variable so then uh once the
mapping plug-in uh set that shared
variable value the virtual table plugin
can pick up the value and use it to
translate uh data vers cruit API into
business Central cruit API so now let me
show you in a demo so in this demo I
will show you first uh the two company
within business Central to show you
different sales invoices that I will um
I will show later in the power Pages
portal addressing those two different
company so for Kronos USA you can see
the sales invoices looks um uh like this
they have like about seven sales um
invoices right and then if I switch to
company to my
company the settings you can see there's
a uh fewer sales
invoices so that way you can remember uh
in the demo which company we be use you
can see here for the my company uh
there's only two sales invoices right so
now I will show you a data verse contact
table where um a user from the customer
of Kronos USA for example that will be
used to access a power Pages portal as
um uh user from um uh from the customer
organization so in this case uh will be
using this one say Robert Townes so
Robert town is is a he's a contact UM
for ad datum corporation which is the
customer for um uh Kronos USA so I will
use his credential as a contact user to
go into a B2B portal created with power
Pages all right and you can see here uh
in order to show only the sales invoices
related to a datam I have to create a
new column in the contacts table in data
verse which is busy customer such that
you can create a syntactic relations
that will only show a datum sales
invoices in the power Pages uh B2B
portal all right next I want I want to
show the BC business Central
configuration app that com with the
virtual table plug-in installation where
you can actually set the global company
settings so in here when you click on
this configuration top you can see that
by default the whole company is U the
the setup for the global company setting
is a kronis USA so that means any apps
on any P PES portal we always show uh
entities say s sales invoices sales
order uh related to Kronos USA and then
if you go to the user table in data
verse and find the user that you want to
use for example mod administrator you
can actually assign a user specific
company setting and here you can see
here there's a company to default on
forms you can actually assign kronus us
or my company or whatever company you
have in business Central and this
setting will override the global
settings okay so that is a user specific
company setting and what I want to show
you right now is the shared variable the
the mapping table that will um be use to
set the uh BC Company ID shared variable
so in here I have um this uh mapping
table and um the mapping table has
Company ID application name that's is
that's for power apps portal ID for
power pages and then user right so in
this uh the in the last two row I
actually have two power Pages portal
with portal ID 1 ec2 and 8818 they are
all targeting different business Central
company so one is targeting my company
the other is targeting uh Kronos USA you
might ask where I can get those um uh
those portal ID I will show you so when
you are actually in the P power Pages
portal you can actually go to the URL
and then add this uh terms uh undor
service slab and then you can actually
see here this is the portal ID for that
website and this one you can do the same
thing to see the portal
ID and you can see it here right so like
this one is one easy2 the other one is
8818 and if you look at the the table
the 8818 is targeting Chronos USA the
one easy to tring my company all right
so now let me um let me just start it
with um uh showing you a demo of the
three different access uh by um
different type of user to business
Central data using power pages so the
first access is a Anonymous access
without signing in so in this case um in
my power Pages uh B2B portal I'm
allowing the business Central item table
to be accessed without any license and
without signing in so if I click on here
and you can see here all the items for
sale that's uh offered by kronis USA and
I can show this data to any external
user with any license because I allow
them to do an anonymous Reon access now
I'm going to sign in as Robert which is
the contact for
adum now Robert is signing in as an adum
uh contact and you can see here it can
only see the S uh well it's still
looking at the item table but now I can
see
invoices and when I go to the invoices
uh page of this portal Robert can only
see invoices related to
aatam you can see here all dis posted
invoice related to uh aatam Corporation
now I'm going to log out and um uh
signing back in as an internal user of
Kronos USA company so let me sign out
and sign in using the Microsoft entra
ID and you can see now the invoices that
I show is actually showing all invoices
for the customer for kronis USA so you
can see the invoices from School of Fine
Art Alpine Ski house as well as adum
Corporation and these invoices are
actually related to the global company
setting that I said before which is the
targeting kronis USA right now what I
wanted to show you is actually uh using
that um mapping table I will show you
that this portal we use kronis USA and
the other portal we use my my company ID
so let's go back here and if I sign in
with the entra Microsoft entra ID it
will check the portal ID and we will it
will look at the Kronos USA um uh
invoices for its customer but if I go to
the other site and I do the same thing
we only use the my company uh invoices
so in this case let me log in with the
same
user there you go so you can see that we
can have
multiple multiple sites targeting
different virtual table uh related to
different business Central company um
setting that we use uh the mapping table
for and the mapping plugin so in this
case uh uh we have concluded the demo of
um of the of this section for power
pages on Virtual tables hope to see you
soon
bye-bye